Guide to the Robert Fitzgerald Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Writings of Robert Fitzgerald, 1926-1984; Series II; 6.88; (17 boxes)
  - TRANSLATIONS
    - Aeneid
      - Setting copy (Random House ed.), with proofreaders' marks and printer's annotations (Box 65, Folder 2403-2406)
      - Page proofs (Random House ed.), 1983 (Box 65, Folder 2407)
      - Page proofs (Random House ed.), 1983 (Box 66, Folder 2408-2409)
      - Books I-II, page proofs, blues (Random House ed.) (Box 66, Folder 2410)
      - Page proofs (Random House ed.), 1983 May (Box 66, Folder 2411-2412)
      - Page proofs (Random House ed.), 1983 Jul (Box 67, Folder 2413-2414)
      - Book Jacket, 1983 (Box 67, Folder 2415)
      - Postscript, draft, typescript, n.d. (Box 67, Folder 2416)
      - Postscript, draft, typescript photocopy, corrected, with list of corrections, 1984 Apr 9 (Box 67, Folder 2417)
      - Postscript, draft, typescript photocopy, with printer's annotations, n.d. (Box 67, Folder 2418)
      - Postscript, setting copy, n.d. (Box 67, Folder 2419)
      - Postscript, page copy, 1984 Apr 12 (Box 67, Folder 2420)
      - Glossary, draft, typescript, corrected, with proofreaders' marks and printer's annotations (Box 67, Folder 2421)
      - Glossary, setting copy, n.d. (Box 67, Folder 2422)
      - [Miscellaneous material], n.d. (Box 67, Folder 2423)
      - Page proofs (Vintage Books ed.), n.d. (Box 68, Folder 2424-2426)
      - Page proofs for frontmatter (Vintage Books ed.), 1984 (Box 68, Folder 2427)
      - Page proofs for postscript and glossary (Vintage Books ed.), 1984
      - Page proofs, blues, n.d. (Box 68, Folder 2428-2429)
      - Book I, page proof (Harvill ed.), 1983 (Box 68, Folder 2430)
      - Page proofs, blues (Harvill ed.), 1984 (Box 69, Folder 2431)
      - Excerpts, 1982 (Box 69, Folder 2432)
      - Book Jacket, 1983 Sep (Box 69, Folder 2433)
      - Printed publicity, 1983 (Box 69, Folder 2434)
      - Reviews, 1983 Nov 28 (Box 69, Folder 2435)
    - The Alcestis of Euripides
      - Draft fragments, typescript and typescript carbon (Box 69, Folder 2436)
      - Reviews, 1936-37 (Box 69, Folder 2437)
    - Antigone of Sophocles
      - Drafts, typescript, [1938-39?] (Box 69, Folder 2438)
      - Publicity, n.d. (Box 69, Folder 2439)
      - Reviews, 1939 (Box 69, Folder 2440)
    - Birds
      - Draft, typescript corrected, photocopy, n.d. (Box 69, Folder 2441)
      - Reviews, 1966, 1968 (Box 69, Folder 2442)
    - Chronique by Saint-John Perse
      - Drafts, typescript and typescript carbon, corrected, 1960, n.d. (Box 69, Folder 2443)
      - Draft, typescript carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 69, Folder 2444)
      - Draft, typescript carbon, corrected, 1960 Nov 4 (Box 69, Folder 2445)
      - Questions and proposed revisions, typescript, corrected, 1960 Oct 31 (Box 69, Folder 2446)
      - Reviews, 1961, n.d. (Box 69, Folder 2447)
    - The Iliad
      - Project and Plans for Work, typescript carbon (2 copies) (Box 69, Folder 2448)
      - Book I, draft, typescript carbon, with annotations by Dudley Fitts, n.d. (Box 69, Folder 2449)
      - Draft, corrected, with proofreaders' marks and printer's annotations, 1974 (Box 69, Folder 2450-2451)
      - Draft, corrected, with proofreaders' marks and printer's annotations, 1974 (Box 70, Folder 2452-2453)
      - Foundry proof, 1974
      - Revised galley proof, 1974
      - Final galley proof, 1974
      - Publicity, 1965 Oct 3 (Box 70, Folder 2454)
      - Reviews, 1976 Sep (Box 70, Folder 2455)
    - The Odyssey
      - Background material, typescript carbon, 1948-56 (Box 70, Folder 2456)
      - List of book titles, draft, typescript carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 70, Folder 2457)
      - List of "People who should get advance copies," typescript carbon, n.d. (Box 70, Folder 2458)
      - Publicity, 1961-62, n.d. (Box 70, Folder 2459)
      - Reviews, 1961, n.d. (Box 70, Folder 2460)
      - "Adoptions of the Odyssey," typescript, n.d. (Box 70, Folder 2461)
    - Oedipus at Colonus
      - Reviews, 1941-57 (Box 70, Folder 2462)
    - "The Gospel at Colonus"
      - Script, typescript [photocopy?], 1983 Sep 26 (Box 70, Folder 2463)
        Includes letter from Liza Lormin
      - Clippings, 1984, n.d. (Box 70, Folder 2464)
    - Other Translations
      - "4. Priam and Achilles," reprint, Aprion, 1967 (Box 70, Folder 2465)
      - "Aeneas at Delos: The Island Voyage ( Aeneid III, 73-130)," typescript, corrected (Box 70, Folder 2466)
      - "The Descent to the Underworld ( Aeneid VI, 237-314)" (Box 70, Folder 2467)
      - "Dunya" and "Secret Croatia" (poem and introduction), drafts, typescript and typescript carbon, corrected, 1969 Dec (Box 70, Folder 2468)
      - "Horace I, 25," printed version, n.d. (Box 70, Folder 2469)
      - "Odisea, Libro Vigesimo Tercero," by Jorge Luis Borges, draft, typescript carbon, 1968 (Box 70, Folder 2470)
      - "Of the Translator," by Jorge Guillén, drafts, typescript and typescript carbon, corrected, 1969 Dec (Box 70, Folder 2471)
      - [On René Char], typescript carbon, n.d. (Box 70, Folder 2472)
        Includes translations, with M. Caetani, of work by René Ménard, Georges Mounin, André Roussant and Fernand Verhesen
      - "Plays," by Paul Valéry, typescript, corrected, and typescript carbon, 1958, n.d. (Box 70, Folder 2473)
      - "The Pyres ( Aeneid Book XI, 182-209)," typescript carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 70, Folder 2474)
      - "The Reading of the Murals ( Aeneid I, 441-497)," typescript, n.d. (Box 70, Folder 2475)
      - "The River Dream ( Aeneid VIII, 1-78)," typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 70, Folder 2476)
      - "Speech Delivered by Saint-John Perse at the Nobel Banquet, December 10, 1960," typescript carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 70, Folder 2477)
      - "Tidings," draft, typescript carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 70, Folder 2478)
      - "To Ainitma the..." draft, holograph, n.d. (Box 70, Folder 2479)
      - "The Trojan and the Sibyl ( Aeneid Book VI)," typescript, corrected, 1982 Dec 5 (Box 70, Folder 2480)
  - OTHER WRITINGS
    - "A Christmas Story," draft, holograph, n.d. (Box 71, Folder 2481)
    - ["Del: myth about BB still..."], draft, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 71, Folder 2482)
    - "Fable I," draft, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 71, Folder 2483)
    - "Foreword" to Samuel Foster Damon's The Moulton Tragedy, draft, typescript carbon, corrected, 1969 Nov (Box 71, Folder 2484)
    - "Heroic Mockery," outline, holograph, 1974 Aug 9 (Box 71, Folder 2485)
    - ["In the mythical history..."], draft, typescript, corrected, 1983 (Box 71, Folder 2485a)
    - ["The Japanese pilots who..."], draft, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 71, Folder 2486)
    - "Robert Browning," draft, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 71, Folder 2487)
    - "The Stiffs," draft, typescript and typescript carbon (Box 71, Folder 2488)
    - "The Test," draft, typescript and typescript carbon (Box 71, Folder 2489)
    - The Third Kind of Knowledge, background material, typescript (Box 71, Folder 2490)
    - "Three Provincial Pearls," typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 71, Folder 2491)
    - "Wisdom and Art," typescript and typescript carbon, corrected (Box 71, Folder 2492)
    - Untitled drafts and draft fragments, holograph and typescript, [1930s?] (Box 71, Folder 2493)
    - Untitled drafts and draft fragments, holograph and typescript, 1974-79, n.d. (Box 71, Folder 2494)
- Writings of Others, 1925-1984; Series III; 2.92; (7 boxes)
  Series III, Writings of Others, is arranged alphabetically by author.
  - Agee, Joel
    - "In a Boat on Glienicker See," poem, galley proof, [1967?] (Box 72, Folder 2495)
  - Agoos, Julie
    - [Poems], drafts, typescript, n.d. (Box 72, Folder 2496)
  - Arnheim, Rudolf
    - "The Gestalt Theory of Expression," article, reprint, Psychological Review, 1949 May (Box 72, Folder 2497)
  - Auden, W. H. (Wystan Hugh)
    - "Ode," poem, printed version, Vindex, photocopy, 1938 Nov (Box 72, Folder 2498)
    - "Romantic or Free," address, printed version, Smith Alumnae Quarterly, photocopy, 1940 Aug (Box 72, Folder 2499)
  - Bacon, Helen H.
    - "The Aeneid as a Drama of Election," article, typescript photocopy, n.d. (Box 72, Folder 2500)
  - Baird, Andrew
    - [Poems], drafts, typescript photocopy, n.d. (Box 72, Folder 2501)
  - Baird, Sarah
    - "Report from Walden and Concord, Massachusetts - 1973," article, typescript photocopy (Box 72, Folder 2502)
  - Barolini, Helen
    - "Xenia," translation of poem by Eugenio Montale, printed version, photocopy, 1977 Oct (Box 72, Folder 2503)
  - Barr, Thomas
    - "Cycles," poem, typescript photocopy, 1977 Apr 25 (Box 72, Folder 2504)
  - Barry, Iris
    - "The Ezra Pound Period," article, printed version, The Bookman, 1931 Oct (Box 72, Folder 2505)
  - Barth, J. Robert
    - "Symbol as Sacrament in Coleridge's Thought," article, offprint, Studies in Romanticism, 1972 (Box 72, Folder 2506)
  - Baumel, Judith
    - "Fractioned Idiom," essay, typescript photocopy, 1976 May 25 (Box 72, Folder 2507)
    - "Message from the Interior," drafts, poems, typescript photocopy, n.d. (Box 72, Folder 2508)
    - [Poems], drafts, typescript and typescript photocopy (Box 72, Folder 2509)
  - Behrends, Sam
    - "A Non-History," poem, typescript copy, n.d. (Box 72, Folder 2510)
  - Bernard, April
    - [Poems], typescript, n.d. (Box 72, Folder 2511)
  - Berryman, John
    - "Antithesis," poem, printed version, The New Yorker, 1970 Jul 25 (Box 72, Folder 2512)
    - "His thought Made Pockets and the Plane Buckt," poem, printed version, 1961 Jun 26 (Box 72, Folder 2513)
    - "Homage to Mistress Bradstreet," draft, poem, typescript carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 72, Folder 2514)
    - ["My daughter's heavier..."], draft, poem, typescript corrected, 1965 (Box 72, Folder 2515)
    - [Poems], printed versions, photocopy, 1970, n.d. (Box 72, Folder 2516)
    - "Posthumous, Dream Songs," poem, galley, corrected, photocopy, 1974 Dec 13 (Box 72, Folder 2517)
    - "Twelve Dream Songs," poem, printed version, photocopy, 1961 (Box 72, Folder 2518)
  - Bidart, April
    - "The War of Vaslav Nijinsky," poem, typescript photocopy, 1980 Nov 4 (Box 72, Folder 2519)
  - Bidart, Frank
    - "Robert Lowell," tribute, typescript photocopy, 1979 Aug 3 (Box 72, Folder 2520)
  - Bishop, Elizabeth
    - "One Art," poem, typescript carbon, 1975 (Box 72, Folder 2521)
    - [Poems], printed versions, 1951-78, n.d. (Box 72, Folder 2522)
  - Bishop, Morris
    - [Poems], printed versions, The New Yorker, 1952, n.d. (Box 72, Folder 2523)
  - [Bloomfield, Morton W. (Morton Wilfrid)?]
    - "Quality in Translation," introduction to study, typescript, corrected, photocopy, [1979 Jan 23?] (Box 72, Folder 2523a)
  - Bogan, Louise
    - "Song for the Last Act," poem, printed version, The New Yorker, n.d. (Box 72, Folder 2524)
  - Boney, William Jerry
    [Poems], drafts, typescript and holograph
    See: Personal Papers, Teaching and Course Material, Box 107, folder 3631
  - Borgese, Nika
    - "The Odyssey," draft, play, holograph, 1955, n.d. (Box 72, Folder 2525)
  - Bottkol, Joseph McG.
    - "The Holograph of Milton's Letter to Holstenius," article, reprint, Publications of the Modern Language Association of American, 1953 Jun (Box 72, Folder 2526)
  - Bozeman, Adda E.
    - "Decline of the West? Spengler Reconsidered," article, printed version, photocopy, 1983 (Box 72, Folder 2527)
  - Breton, André
    - "Pour un Art Révolutionnaire Indépendant," printed version, 1938 Jul 25 (Box 72, Folder 2527a)
      With Diego Rivera
  - Brinnin, John Malcolm
    - "A Thin Façade for Edith Sitwell," poem, printed version, The New Yorker, n.d. (Box 72, Folder 2528)
  - Bromwich, David
    - "Three Unlikely Stanzas on the Nativity," poem, typescript, 1975 (Box 72, Folder 2529)
  - Brown, Harry
    - "An Obliging Captain, Sailing Light," poem, reprint, The Hudson Review, 1974 Feb (Box 72, Folder 2530)
  - Budenz, Julia
    - "The Fire Escape," poem, offprint, Studia Mystica, 1980 (Box 72, Folder 2531)
  - Buitoni, Raimonda
    - [Poems], drafts, typescript, 1969, 1971 (Box 72, Folder 2532)
  - Byrd, Max
    - "Metamorphosis and Tintern Abbey: Two Notes," article reprint, Modern Philology, 1983 Aug (Box 72, Folder 2533)
      See also: Correspondence, Byrd, Max, Box 6, Folder 214
  - Caplan, Cilla
    - [Poems and dialogue], drafts, typescript photocopy (Box 72, Folder 2534)
  - Carrier, Constance
    - "Women," poem, typescript mimeograph, 1977 Apr (Box 72, Folder 2535)
  - [Cavafy, Constantine]
    - [ The Telos of Odysseus ?], printed version, with presentation inscription from G.P. Savvides, 1974 (Box 72, Folder 2536)
  - Chasin, Helen
    - [Poems], drafts, typescript, typescript carbon, and typescript photocopy, 1970 (Box 72, Folder 2537)
  - Codman, Florence
    - "Columnists," article, typescript carbon, n.d. (Box 72, Folder 2538)
  - Collingwood, Harris
    - [Poems], drafts, typescript photocopies, n.d. (Box 72, Folder 2539)
  - Cook, Jonathan
    - "Studies in Homer's Odyssey," essay, typescript corrected, photocopy, 1982 Nov 22 (Box 72, Folder 2540)
      See also: Correspondence, Cook, Jonathan, Box 7, Folder 302
  - Cooke, Michael G.
    - [Poems], printed versions, 1976 (Box 72, Folder 2541)
  - Corke, Hilary
    - "Waiting," poem, printed version, 1960 Jul (Box 72, Folder 2542)
  - Cousins, Norman
    - "Ezra Pound and the Bollingen Award," open letter, printed version, Saturday Review at Literature, 1949 Jun 11 (Box 72, Folder 2543)
  - Cummings, E. E. (Edward Estlin)
    - "Ten Poems," galley proof, 1963
  - D'Almeida, George
    - "The Gospel of Jude," poems, [printout?], 1982 Oct (Box 72, Folder 2544)
    - "Memoirs of a Spartan Snow," poems, drafts, [printouts?], 1983-84 (Box 73, Folder 2545)
  - Davison, Peter
    - [Poems], drafts, typescript, 1969-81 (Box 73, Folder 2546)
    - "Wordless Winter," poems, reprint, The Hudson Review, 1981 Feb 13 (Box 73, Folder 2547)
  - Devlin, Denis
    - "The Tomb of Michael Collins," poem, reprint, The Sewanee Review, 1956 (Box 73, Folder 2548)
  - Dey, Richard
    - "The Bequia Poems," printed version, 1979 (Box 73, Folder 2549)
    - "On Sailing," [story?], typescript, corrected, 1973 Nov (Box 73, Folder 2550)
    - [Poems], drafts, typescript and typescript photocopy (Box 73, Folder 2551)
    - ["The Sea and I..."], autobiographical statement, typescript photocopy, 1973 Jan (Box 73, Folder 2552)
  - Dickey, James
    - "The Strength of Fields," poem, printed version, n.d. (Box 73, Folder 2553)
  - Dillard, Annie
    - "For the Love of China," article, printed version, Harvard Magazine, 1983 (Box 73, Folder 2554)
    - "Total Eclipse," story, printed version, Antaeus, photocopy, 1982 Mar (Box 73, Folder 2555)
  - Du Béarn, Roger
    - "Limerique," poem, printed version, n.d. (Box 73, Folder 2556)
  - Eberhart, Richard
    - "Inchiquin Lake, Penobscot Bay," poem, printed version, photocopy, 1974 Jan 25 (Box 73, Folder 2557)
  - Eliot, T. S. (Thomas Stearns)
    - "The Love Song of J. Alfred Prufrock," copy, typescript, 1925 (Box 73, Folder 2558)
  - [Ellman, Richard?]
    - ["You who didn't actually know..."], public program script, typescript, n.d. (Box 73, Folder 2559)
  - English, Maurice
    - "In the Operating Room," printed version, The American Scholar, photocopy, 1973 (Box 73, Folder 2560)
  - Erikson, Kai
    - ["Yale Review is about..."], article, typescript photocopy, 1981 (Box 73, Folder 2561)
  - Felstiner, John
    - "Translating Pablo Neruda's "Galope muerto"," article, printed version, n.d. (Box 73, Folder 2562)
  - Fergusson, Francis
    - "Randall Jarrell and the Flotations of Voice," article, printed version, photocopy, 1974 (Box 73, Folder 2563)
    - "A Suite for Winter," poem, reprint, The Sewanee Review, 1955 (Box 73, Folder 2564)
  - Fitts, Dudley
    - [Poems], drafts, typescript and typescript carbon (Box 73, Folder 2565)
    - [Other writings], drafts, typescript and typescript carbon (Box 73, Folder 2566)
  - Fox, Ruth Berrien
    - "Paganini Variations," poem, printed version, 1967 (Box 73, Folder 2567)
    - "Sunset at Sounion," typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 73, Folder 2568)
  - Frost, Robert
    - ["Nature's first green..."], poem, holograph in unidentified hand, 1975 Mar (Box 73, Folder 2569)
  - Gaitanis, Louis A.
    - "Come Join the Circling Dancers," poem, printed version, photocopy, 1975 Aug 5 (Box 73, Folder 2570)
  - Gioia, Dana
    - "An Elegy for Vladimir de Pachmann," poem, reprint, 1981 (Box 73, Folder 2571)
      God Only Knows Lives of the Great Composers Photograph of My Mother as a Young Girl View from the Second Story
    - [Poems], typescript and printed version, photocopies, 1980, n.d. (Box 73, Folder 2572)
    - "Poetry Chronicle," article, reprint, Hudson Review, 1981 (Box 73, Folder 2573)
  - Giroux, Robert
    - "The Book Known as Q," article, typescript photocopy, corrected, 1979 Jun (Box 73, Folder 2574)
  - Glück, Louise
    - "Night Songs," poem, printed version, [ The New Yorker ?], 1983 Oct 24 (Box 73, Folder 2575)
  - Goodman, Alice
    - "The Chemical Blonde," thesis, typescript photocopy, 1980 Apr 10 (Box 73, Folder 2576)
    - "Dog and Sugar," draft, poem, typescript (Box 73, Folder 2577)
  - Graham, Debby
    - "The Ascent to Charlie's Aria," poem, printed version, 1976 Nov 11 (Box 73, Folder 2578)
  - Graves, Robert
    - [Poems], printed versions, n.d. (Box 73, Folder 2579)
  - Gray, Elizabeth
    - [Poems], drafts, typescript and typescript photocopy, 1977 Dec (Box 73, Folder 2580)
  - Green, Jeffrey Martin
    - "An Early French Translation of De Oficiis," article, reprint, 1976 Mar 12 (Box 73, Folder 2581)
  - Gregory, Horace
    - "Dedication for My Daughter," poem, typescript carbon, n.d. (Box 73, Folder 2582)
    - "Introduction" to New Letters in America, printed version, photocopy, n.d. (Box 73, Folder 2583)
  - Grossman, Allen
    - "Of the Great House," poems, typescript photocopy, n.d. (Box 73, Folder 2584)
  - Guenther, John
    - "South," poem, typescript [photocopy?], 1976 Feb 25 (Box 73, Folder 2585)
  - Hamilton, Gertrude Brooke
    - "A Rhyme at Twilight," poem, printed version, n.d. (Box 73, Folder 2586)
  - [Hamilton, Ian?]
    - "Robert Lowell: A Biography," galley proof, photocopy, 1982 Jun 27 (Box 73, Folder 2587)
  - Hammond, Mason
    - "A Famous Exemplum of Spartan Toughness," article, offprint, 1980 Jan 25 (Box 73, Folder 2588)
  - Hass, Robert
    - "Heroic Simile," poem, reprint, 1976 (Box 73, Folder 2589)
  - Heaney, Seamus
    - "Changes," poem, printed version, 1980 (Box 73, Folder 2590)
    - "Robert Lowell," speech, printed version, 1978 May 12 (Box 73, Folder 2591)
  - Hecht, Anthony
    - "Behold the Lilies of the Field," poem, typescript carbon, 1969 (Box 73, Folder 2592)
  - Heilman, Robert B.
    - "Football: An Addict's Memoirs and Observations," article, offprint, The Journal of American Culture, 1982 Jun 25 (Box 73, Folder 2593)
    - "Robert Fitzgerald," introduction, [typescript photocopy?], 1982 (Box 73, Folder 2594)
  - Hering, Frank E.
    - "Sweetie: A Little Bird," story, printed version, n.d. (Box 74, Folder 2595)
  - Herrington, John
    - "Litterae Inhumaniores," article, printed version, photocopy, 1982 (Box 74, Folder 2596)
  - Hersey, John
    - "Henry Luce's China Dream," printed version, The New Republic, 1983 May 2 (Box 74, Folder 2597)
  - Herzberg, Judith
    - "Orpheus," translation of poem by Hunk Oosterhuis, typescript, n.d. (Box 74, Folder 2598)
  - Hicks, Greenwich
    - "A Letter to Robert Hillyer," printed version, The New Republic, 1937 Oct 20 (Box 74, Folder 2599)
  - Hillyer, Robert
    - [Poems], printed version, n.d. (Box 74, Folder 2600)
    - "Poetry's New Priesthood," article, printed version, Saturday Review of Literature, 1949 Jun 18 (Box 74, Folder 2601)
    - "Treason's Strange Fruit," article, printed version, Saturday Review of Literature, 1949 Jun 11 (Box 74, Folder 2602)
  - Hoffman, Daniel
    - "The Center of Attention," poem, printed version, 1974 (Box 74, Folder 2603)
  - Hogan, James C.
    - "Aristotle's Criticism of Homer in the Poetics ," article, reprint, Classical Philology, 1973 Apr (Box 74, Folder 2604)
    - "Double .... and the Language of Achilles," article, offprint, 1976 May (Box 74, Folder 2605)
  - Hollander, John
    - "After an Old Text," poem, printed version, 1977 Jan (Box 74, Folder 2606)
    - "A Glimpse of Proserpina," poem, printed version, The New Yorker, n.d. (Box 74, Folder 2607)
  - [Hood, Thomas?]
    - ["My temples throb..."], poem, typescript, [transcription?], n.y. Jan 15 (Box 74, Folder 2608)
  - Howard, Vilma A.
    - "The Lesson," poem, typescript carbon, 1950 May (Box 74, Folder 2609)
  - Howe, Fanny
    - "Out of the Cradle Endlessly Rocking," typescript photocopy, 1977 Dec (Box 74, Folder 2610)
  - Howes, Barbara
    - "Two Poems," printed version, 1962 (Box 74, Folder 2611)
  - Humphries, Rolfe
    - "Arachne and Penelope," poem, printed version (Box 74, Folder 2612)
  - Hutchins, Robert [Maynard?]
    - "A Free and Responsible Press," reprint (Box 74, Folder 2612a)
  - Hynson, Garret P.
    - "Dreams Have No Beginning but They End," [story?], typescript carbon (Box 74, Folder 2613)
  - Jackson, Laura Riding
    - "End-of-Year, Holiday-Time, Story," holograph, photocopy, 1971 Dec 18 (Box 74, Folder 2614)
    - "Statement by Laura (Riding) Jackson," typescript, photocopy, 1977 Oct 17 (Box 74, Folder 2615)
  - Jackson, Schuyler
    - "The Latest in Symphony," article, printed version, 1942 Nov (Box 74, Folder 2616)
  - James, Thomas
    - [Poems], drafts, typescript, n.d. (Box 74, Folder 2617)
  - Jameson, M. H.
    - "Politics and the Philoctetes," article, reprint from Classical Philology, 1956 Oct (Box 74, Folder 2618)
  - Janowitz, T.
    - "The Only Norm is Perpetual Variation," story, typescript photocopy, n.d. (Box 74, Folder 2619)
  - Jarrell, Randall
    - ["There are three stages..."], lectures on Auden, typescript carbon and typescript photocopy, 1952 (Box 74, Folder 2620)
  - Johnson, Amy
    - "Theocritean Pastoral," article, typescript photocopy, corrected, 1976 Dec (Box 74, Folder 2621)
  - Johnston, Charles
    - "Choiseul and Talleyrand," poem, typescript corrected, photocopy (Box 74, Folder 2622)
  - Jones, Tom
    - "The Muse," poem, typescript, 1976 (Box 74, Folder 2623)
  - Josipovici, Gabriel
    - "Vergil Dying," article, offprint, n.d. (Box 74, Folder 2624)
  - Justice, Donald
    - "First Death," poem, printed version, The Ohio Review, corrected, 1977 Apr 24 (Box 74, Folder 2625)
  - Karasz, Alison
    - [Poems], drafts, typescript photocopy, 1977 Aug (Box 74, Folder 2626)
  - Karmel, Pepe
    - "The Prodigal," poem, typescript corrected, 1977 Oct (Box 74, Folder 2627)
  - Katz, Claire
    - "Flannery O'Connor's Rage of Vision," article, reprint, American Literature, 1974 (Box 74, Folder 2628)
  - Kayden, Eugene
    - "Sixteen Poems," translation, reprint, The Colorado Quarterly, 1973 (Box 74, Folder 2629)
  - Keeley, Edmund
    - "The Alexandrian," book proposal, typescript photocopy (Box 74, Folder 2630)
    - "At Home in a Greek Village," article, printed version, n.d.
    - "A Lyric, Poetic Greek Voice That Has a Special Texture," article printed version, 1979 Oct (Box 74, Folder 2631)
    - [Poems], translations of Giannos Ritsos, typescript photocopy, 1966 (Box 74, Folder 2632)
  - Kirk, G. S. [(Geoffrey Stephen)?]
    - "Introduction," printed version, photocopy, n.d. (Box 74, Folder 2633)
  - [Kirk?], ----
    - "Fratres Minores," poem, typescript, n.d. (Box 74, Folder 2634)
  - Kirschner, Anne
    - [Poems], typescript and holograph, photocopy, 1982 Feb 21 (Box 74, Folder 2635)
  - Kizer, Carolyn
    - "Afternoon Happiness," poem, printed version, 1982 (Box 74, Folder 2636)
    - "From Pro Femina," poem, printed version, photocopy, n.d. (Box 74, Folder 2637)
  - Klappert, Peter